Must read [Terms of Service](https://writeaprisoner.com/terms-service) & [Privacy Policy](https://writeaprisoner.com/privacy-policy) and be at least 18

User account menu
-----------------

Must read [Terms of Service](https://writeaprisoner.com/) &  
[Privacy Policy](https://writeaprisoner.com/) and be at least 18

Must read [Terms of Service](https://writeaprisoner.com/terms-service) & [Privacy Policy](https://writeaprisoner.com/privacy-policy) and be at least 18

User account menu
-----------------

Must read [Terms of Service](https://writeaprisoner.com/) &  
[Privacy Policy](https://writeaprisoner.com/) and be at least 18

Main navigation
---------------

MENU

Privacy Policy
==============

**Last Updated June 22, 2024**

We take user privacy seriously and want you to be informed. This Privacy Policy (the "**Privacy Policy**"), which is incorporated into our [Terms of Service](https://writeaprisoner.com/terms-service) and which includes definitions applicable to this Privacy Policy, explains how WriteAPrisoner.com, Inc. (“**WriteAPrisoner**,” “**Company**,” “**we**,” “**our**,” or “**us**”) collects, uses, shares, and protects information of the users of WriteAPrisoner.com and all other sites, mobile sites, services, applications, platforms, and tools where this Privacy Policy appears or is linked (collectively, the “**Website**”). The terms “**you/your/user(s)**” means you as a user of our Website.

By accessing the Website, you acknowledge this Privacy Policy and agree to be bound by its terms, our Terms of Service, and any other terms or policies we post on the Website. If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Website or provide us with any personal information.

**Who controls your information?**

Any information or other data provided to or gathered by Company is controlled by:

WriteAPrisoner.com, Inc.   
P.O. Box 10  
Edgewater, FL 32132-0010  
United States  
[\[email protected\]](https://writeaprisoner.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

**What types of information do we collect?**

“**Information**,” as used in this Privacy Policy, means personal information that identifies, relates to, describes, is capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with a particular user or household.

We collect and/or have collected the following categories of information about you and other users of the Website:

* **Information You Provide to Us.** We collect information from you when you voluntarily provide it to us over the Website, including as part of registering a user Account. Such information may include your name, email address, telephone number(s), street address, city, and state. Additionally, if you are an inmate, we may collect your eye color, hair color, hometown, date of birth, the address you plan to reside upon release, your earliest release date, your latest release date, your incarcerated since date, whether you are serving a life sentence or if you are on death row, and your criminal history including the crime you were arrested for, the arresting agency, and the city and state where the crime was committed.
* **Content You Make Public.** Company collects information from you that you voluntarily upload to the Website for public display (“**Public Information**”), such as your Content, which may include posts, comments, photos, text, and artwork. Once you submit Public Information, neither you nor Company are able to control how it may be copied, shared, or used by third parties, even if you and/or Company later delete such Public Information. Accordingly, you should carefully consider what personal information you choose to make public.
* **Transaction and Payment Information.** We collect information from you, as needed, to process payments to administer your participation on the Website, such as your bank account number, payment card number, expiration date, card verification number, and billing address. Specifically, we use third-party integration through Authorize.Net to process payments. For more information about Authorize.Net’s privacy practices, visit https://usa.visa.com/legal/privacy-policy.html.
* **Device/Internet Connection Information.** When you use the Website, we automatically gather information made available by your web browser (such as Microsoft Edge or Google Chrome), internet service provider (such as Comcast or Cox), and device (such as your computer, phone, tablet, or fitness tracker), depending on your settings for each. For example, we may collect your IP address, information about the operating system or type of device you use, the device ID associated with your device, the date and time you access the Website, and your log in attempts. 
* **Internet Activity Information.** As explained below, we may also collect information about your browsing history, search history, and information regarding your interaction with a particular website, application, or advertisement, including the Website. We may collect information regarding the websites, application, or advertisement you visited immediately before and after your use of the Website.
* **Geolocation Information.** We may collect information about where you are located, both generally and at the time you access the Website. For example, we may collect your mailing address or ascertain your approximate location from your IP address.
* **Protected Class Information.** Due to the specific nature of our services, you may be asked to provide information about your race, ethnicity, nationality, gender, age, marital or family status, sexual orientation, religion, and/or whether you served in the military.
* **Education and Employment Information.** We may collect information about your educational background including your highest level of education, previous schools attended, your education goals, whether you are currently in school, and any recent educational accomplishments. We may also collect your employment history and employment goals.
* **Other Information.** From time to time, we may collect other information from you, such as when you make a claim for a promotion run on the Website, when you request assistance through our Website, or when you voluntarily subscribe to promotions, reminders, or newsletters. You will always be asked for your consent in advance.

**How do we collect information about you?**

We gather information about you through the following sources and means:

* **When you provide information.** Company collects information when users voluntarily enter or upload it while using the Website, such as information you provide, Public Information, transaction and payment information, geolocation information, protected class information, and education and employment information.
* **When you communicate with us.** We may collect information from you outside of your use of the Website, such as if you email us (or respond to a communication) or communicate with us over social media. Information collected outside your use of the Website may be combined with information collected through your use of the Website —for example, if you create an Account through the Website and later contact us about your Account, the information collected in both interactions may be linked.
* **Information from Third Parties.** We may collect information about you from third parties or other sources, such as when an individual creates an Account on behalf of an inmate or other publicly available information about you, including but not limited to, your photo, biographical information, criminal background, and general geographic location or place of incarceration.  
* **Information from your use of our Website.** We may use various technologies to collect and store information when you use, access, or interact with our Website. This may include using cookies or similar technologies to identify your browser or device. In addition, we may collect information from or about the computers, phones, or other devices when you access our Website such as the operating system, hardware version, device settings, device identifiers, language and time zone, mobile phone number, IP address, and server logs.
* **Through cookies, tracking tools, and other automated technologies.** When you use any website, certain information can be automatically collected through technological means. When you access our Website, your web browser automatically sends us device and internet connection information and certain internet activity information. We also use cookies and web beacon technology to gather device and internet connection information, internet activity information, and geolocation information. Please see the section below to learn more about how we use cookies.
* **From Third Parties.** We may collect the following types of information from Third Parties: transaction and payment information (such as when you have your payment information saved in your web browser), device/internet connection information, internet activity information, and geolocation information.

**How do we use cookies and similar technologies?**  

As with many companies, we may use cookies, pixels, gifs, web beacons, log files, and/or similar technologies to automatically collect certain information when you use the Website or interact with our digital media content. This allows us to track individual users, determine when content is accessed, and customize user experiences. For example, unless you have opted out of cookies or changed your cookie settings in your internet browser, your browser automatically sends us certain device, browser, internet connection, and general geolocation information and certain internet activity information. For instance, we may collect your mobile device identifier or MAC address, ISP carrier information, date and time you access the Website, the pages you visit, and whether you click on ads. You can change your cookie settings in your internet browser and use settings on your device to manage your privacy controls. For more information and ways to opt out, see [https://www.allaboutcookies.org/](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/), and learn how to disable these tools by opting-out of [third-party cookies](http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2&lang=EN) and [mobile device ID practices](https://youradchoices.com/appchoices).

As part of our practices, we may use third-party advertising companies to display ads tailored to your individual interests based on your online activity and to provide ad-related services such as analytics and market research. Third parties, in turn, may use a cookie, web beacon, or other similar technology to collect information. To opt-out of cross-device linking, visit [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices) or perform a global opt-out on each browser and device.

In particular, we may use Google cookies and tools, such as Google Analytics for analytics and advertising and to improve the user experience, and your information may be shared with Google; for more information, visit the [Google Cookie Policy](https://policies.google.com/technologies/cookies?hl=en-US), [Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-On](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout), or [Ads Settings](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated). We may also use Meta and other cookies for the purposes stated above, and your information from cookies may be shared with Meta; for more information visit the [Meta/Facebook Cookie Policy](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/).

Please note that there are different types of cookies and related technologies, which may be placed by us or third parties, including essential cookies that are required to display and provide the Website; preference cookies that are used to store preferences and improve user experience; analytics cookies to determine how the Website is used and which often collect non-personalized information; and marketing cookies to deliver personalized and targeted advertisements that may be of interest to you and others and which are used for business purposes for advertising to those that visit the Website and commercial purposes for marketing to others.

**How do we use your information?**

WriteAPrisoner may use the information we’ve gathered from you or your device, including through cookies and third parties, for the following purposes:

| **Business Purposes.** When we use your information for a “**Business Purpose**,” it means such use is reasonably necessary and proportionate to achieve an operational purpose of the Company. The following are the Business Purposes for which we may use your information:<br><br>**Business Purpose** | **Types of Information** |
| --- | --- |
| **For Security.** Company uses the information we collect from you and other users to detect security incidents, protect against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity, and to identify and prosecute those responsible for that activity. | Information Outlined Above. |
| **To Provide the Website and Services.** We use the information we collect from you to provide the Website and our services, to process your orders and payments, and to create your account. | Information Outlined Above. |
| **To Improve our Services.** Company uses the information we collect from you and other users to improve our product offerings and services. For example, we may consider analytics, demographics, and user feedback collected via the Website in determining whether there is sufficient demand for new features, connect you with the types of services you’re looking for, and any other content in which you are interested. | Information Outlined Above. |
| **To Improve the Website.** Company uses the information we collect from you and other users to provide and improve the Website.  We use information to debug and identify and repair errors that impair the existing intended functionality of the Website. As explained above, we use cookies, including those placed by Third Parties, to gather statistical information that helps us understand how you and other users engage with the Website and improve its performance via technological development. | Information Outlined Above. |
| **To Personalize Your User Experience.** We use information gathered from Cookies to authenticate your logins, determine whether you are logged in or not, to allow you to set personal preferences when using the Website, and to make it so you don’t have to reenter the same information when you visit the Website several times within a short time frame. | Information Outlined Above. |
| **To Communicate with You.** We use your information to personalize communication with you, and to respond to your requests regarding the Website and your Account. We also use your information to notify you of updates to our Terms or Privacy Policy. | Information Outlined Above. |

| **Commercial Purposes.** When we use your information for a “**Commercial Purpose**,” it means such use is intended to advance Company’s business interests. The following are the Commercial Purposes for which we may use your information:<br><br>**Commercial Purpose** | **Types of Information** |
| --- | --- |
| **To Advertise to Others.** We may share your reviews, comments, and other content uploaded by you to advertise and market our Website, including by reposting your reviews on the Website, in our advertising, or through our social media accounts. | Information Outlined Above. |
| **To Operate Advertising and Marketing Campaigns.** We may use your information to perform and measure the effectiveness of advertising campaigns on our Website and marketing campaigns promoting our Website on and off our services. We may also use your information to communicate with you about products or services that we believe may interest you. | Information Outlined Above. |

**Scope and Legal Bases for Use.** WriteAPrisoner only processes your information to the extent that is necessary to accomplish the above-stated Business and Commercial Purposes, which serves as our legitimate interest. If you reside in a location governed by the GDPR, then the following are Company’s legal bases for the processing of your information: In so far as we have obtained consent for processing operations of information by the data subject, Art. 6(1) lit. a GDPR serves as the legal basis. For the processing of information necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is a party, Art. 6(1) lit. b GDPR serves as legal basis. The same applies to such processing operations which are necessary for carrying out pre-contractual measures. In so far as the processing of information is required to comply with a legal obligation to which our Company is subject, Art. 6(1) lit. c GDPR serves as legal basis. In the event that processing of information may be necessary to protect the vital interests of the data subject or of another natural person, Art. 6(1) lit. d GDPR serves as legal basis. If processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by our Company or by a Third Party, except where such interests are overridden by the interests or fundamental rights and freedoms of the data subject, processing operations are based on Art 6 (1) lit. f GDPR.

**How do we share your information?**

Non-incarcerated persons use our Website to search for inmates to correspond with. Any information included in an inmate’s profile, including their name, photo, biography, criminal background, and location can be seen by all visitors and users of the Website.

In addition to the foregoing, WriteAPrisoner may share your information with third parties for business and commercial purposes.

As part of our business, we disclose information as follows and for the purposes outlined above, which include business purposes to provide and improve the Website and comply with legal and contractual obligations as well as commercial purposes, such as to market our business.

* **_Service Providers and Contractors_**: We share information with service providers, allows us to provide and improve the Website. Service providers only use your information for a contracted-business purpose. Such disclosure is for our business purposes, in particular to provide you with the Website. We may likewise share information with “contractors” that are not service providers but to whom we disclose information for a business purpose. Such disclosure is for business purposes of providing you with services that you have requested or considered.
* **_Company Parties; Merger or Sale_****.** We may share information with affiliated companies that are related to us under a common ownership where they comply with this Privacy Policy. Such disclosure is for our business purposes, including to provide and improve our offers. Further, we may share information as part of a sale, merger, acquisition, or other change in control or entity status, either in whole or in part. We reserve the right to transfer or assign your information as part of any such transaction or investigation.  
     
* **_Cookies/Device Data._** For more information about our use of cookies and other technologies, see above. Such disclosure is for our business purposes, in particular to provide you with the Website, as well as commercial purposes, such as to market to consumers that may be interested in our Website or related offers. Company may also contract with third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our behalf. These companies may use cookies or other measures to collect non-identifier information.  
     
* **_Legal Process and Protection_****.** We may disclose information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, such as to respond to government requests, law enforcement inquiries, legal processes, subpoenas, and court orders. We may disclose information when we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or respond to illegal, fraudulent, or injurious actions or security incidents that may cause harm to us, the Service, or others. We may also disclose information in good faith where necessary to investigate or enforce a violation of this Privacy Policy, our terms, or any legal rights.  
     
* **_Third Parties._** We may disclose information to third parties that could choose to provide unrelated goods or services or for cross-context advertising purposes. Examples include using customer email addresses to allow cross-context advertising for services related to our Website that may be of interest to you. Such disclosure facilitates our Website as well as marketing/commercial purposes.  
     
* **_Consent._** We may disclose information as requested or consented to by you. Such disclosure may be for any business or commercial purpose as described to you.

**Do we sell your information to others?**

We do not sell data for monetary consideration. We only share data as outlined in this Privacy Policy. Our use of online tracking technologies may be considered a “sale” / “sharing” under applicable law. Visitors to our website can opt out of being tracked by these third parties by clicking the "Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information" link at the bottom of our website, or by contacting us as outlined below.

**How do we protect your information?**

We have implemented appropriate security measures designed to protect the security of any personal information we process. However, it is impossible to guarantee the safety of data. We will do our best to protect your information, but the safety and security of your information also depends on you. Never share your password with anyone else and notify us as soon as possible if you believe your account security has been breached.

**How long do we keep your information?**

WriteAPrisoner retains your information for the length of time necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law or valid court order. When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your information, we will delete it, or, if this is not possible (for example because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your information until deletion is possible.

We use the following criteria to determine how long we retain personal information: (a) our relationship with you, such as if there is an open contract or account or a pending transaction or request, (b) legal obligations to retain personal information for certain purposes, such as to maintain transaction records, and (c) other obligations or considerations relating to the retention of data, such as contract requirements, litigation holds, investigations, or statutes of limitation.

**Do we transfer your information to a different country?**

If you are visiting the Website from a location outside of the United States, your connection will be through and to servers located in the United States, and all information you provide will be processed and securely maintained in our web servers and internal systems located within the United States. By using the Website, **you authorize and specifically consent to the transfer of personal data to the United States** and its storage and use as specified above when you provide such information to us.

**What are your privacy rights?**

Based on the state or country you are located in, you may have the right to request access to the personal information we collect from you, request changes to your personal information, or in some circumstances request deletion. To request to review, update, or delete your personal information, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://writeaprisoner.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). We will respond to your request within 30 days.

If you are in the European Union, you have certain rights under the GDPR. Under the GDPR you may have the right to request access to and obtain a copy of your personal information we have collected, request rectification or erasure of your personal information, restrict the processing of your personal information, and, if applicable, request data portability. In certain circumstances, you may also have the right to object to the processing of your personal information. To make any of the above requests, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://writeaprisoner.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). We will consider and act upon any request in accordance with applicable data protection laws. For purposes of this section, your data controller is WriteAPrisoner.com, Inc.

If you have any questions about your privacy rights, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://writeaprisoner.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

**Privacy Practices of Third Parties**

Our Website may include advertisements, content, or links to content, products or services provided by third parties. This Privacy Policy only addresses the use and disclosure of information by WriteAPrisoner through your interaction with the Website. Third-Party Services that may be accessible through links from our Website have their own privacy policies and information collection, use, and disclosure practices. Third-party sellers, advertisers, and partners also have their own privacy practices. We encourage you to familiarize yourself with the privacy statements provided by these third parties prior to providing them with information or taking advantage of a third-party offer or promotion.

**How do we protect the privacy of children?**

WriteAPrisoner does not knowingly collect any personal information about children under the age of 18. If we obtain actual knowledge that we have collected information about a child under the age of 18, that information will be immediately deleted from our database. Because we do not collect such information, we have no such information to use or to disclose to third parties.

**How do we use or disclose sensitive information?**

We do not generally use or disclose “sensitive” personal information, nor do we use sensitive information for purposes other than the following: (a) to perform certain services, such as verifying information or for analytics, (b) to verify or maintain the quality or safety of our Website, (c) to perform services or provide goods reasonably expected, (d) for short-term, transient use where there is no disclosure or profiling, and (e) to resist malicious, fraudulent, or illegal actions or to ensure physical safety.

**How can you receive and opt-out from marketing communications?**

By providing your contact information through the Website or an email initiated by you, **you consent to receive emails from us, including information concerning your account and advertising messages.** Depending upon your location, we may obtain additional consent from you via a checkbox disclosure or an email requesting confirmation before you can receive such information.

Providing consent to promotional emails is NOT a condition of purchasing any goods or services from WriteAPrisoner. You can unsubscribe to advertising emails at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link within the email, or by contacting us at [\[email protected\]](https://writeaprisoner.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). Please note that, even if you unsubscribe from advertising emails, we will still send you any necessary, non-promotional emails about your purchase, account, or updates to our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service.

**Do we respond to Do Not Track (DNT) Signals?**

DNT is a feature offered by some browsers which, when enabled, sends a signal to websites to request that your browsing is not tracked.  We do not respond to DNT requests.

**How will you know when we change the Privacy Policy?**

Each time you use the Website, the then-current version of this Privacy Policy will apply.  Although most changes are likely to be minor, we reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy by posting such modification on this page; however, if changes are significant, we may provide a more prominent notice or email you. Depending upon your location, we may obtain additional consent from you via a checkbox disclosure or an email requesting consent before you can continue to use the Website.

Unless we receive your express consent, any revised Privacy Policy will apply only to information collected after the effective date of such revised Privacy Policy, and not to information collected under any earlier version.

**How can you contact us regarding this Privacy Policy?**

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, you may contact us using the information below.

By Email: [\[email protected\]](https://writeaprisoner.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)  
  
Contact Form: [https://writeaprisoner.com/contact](https://writeaprisoner.com/contact)  
  
By Postal Mail:  
WriteAPrisoner.com, Inc.   
P.O. Box 10  
Edgewater, FL 32132-0010  
United States

Must be 18 to view this website. Use implies acceptance of our [Terms of Service](https://writeaprisoner.com/terms-service) & [Privacy Policy](https://writeaprisoner.com/privacy-policy). Cookies, related technologies, & device identification are used for personalized advertising. To opt out, visit [Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information](https://writeaprisoner.com/form/do-not-sell-or-share-my-personal).

Accept All Cookies

Accept Cookies  

Reject Optional Cookies

Footer
------

2000-2024 WriteAPrisoner.com. Inc. All Rights Reserved.
